IOS DEVELOPER - ALEX MCPHERSON

Phone:

07516 - 797245

Email:

alexmcpherson1980@g maill.com

Address:

74 Sir John Killick Road, Ashford, Kent, TN23 3AQ

PROFILE

A mobile applications developer with over 10 years experience. Actively seeking to turn a passion for mobile, 3D and Augmented Reality into a full-time career.

I have a personal interest in all things 3D including AR, VR, 3D modelling and printing. Other interests include Mechanical Engineering, Mechatronics and Robotics using microcontrollers such as the Arduino.

EXPERIENCE

iOS Developer — WorldPay (FIS) — London — 2018 - Present

- Worked as part of a large mobile development team of over 20 developers/testers
- Developed and maintained WorldPay POS (Point of sale) SDKs and App in Objective-C and Swift
- Developed and maintained WorldPay Total Mobile SDKs in Swift
- Solely developed a AR (Augmented Reality) app in SwiftUI and UIKit to demo our WorldPay payment APIs around the globe. See video here
- Developed and maintained SoftPOS Mobile application in Kotlin (Android)
- Worked with private/public pods CocoaPods Dependancy Manager
- · Daily Code reviews of iOS and Android projects
- Document iOS coding best practices
- Liaise with Test teams and Project Managers and advise on bug fixes and future improvements
- Work in an Agile/SAFe environment, SCRUM and daily standup with the team and various stakeholders
- · Weekly/Bi-Weekly Sprint planning and refinement
- · Update Jira and Rally for project management
- · Contribute to PI planning
- Contribute to Demo and Retrospective ceremonies
- Git Source control for all WorldPay repos
- · CI administration using Bitrise

Recycle For [Ashford, Maidstone, Southampton, Burnley and Canterbury councils] - 2010

- Conceptualised, developed, designed and sold a waste management system for local government authorities in the UK
- Developed and maintained iOS client facing app for waste management written in Objective-C
- Developed and maintained iOS local authority app for managing waste management and street scene events written in Objective-C
- Meetings with a large number of stakeholders to demo and sell the solution
- The apps where featured in media around the world

Presteigne Charter - Rate Card - 2010

- Developed a iPhone app to catalogue their huge catalogue of rental audio/visual equipment that supplied major film studios and broadcasters such as SKY and the BBC.
- Attended regular meetings with stakeholders on progress of the app
- Supported the app for several years and updated the data on a fairly regular basis as it had no backend and data was exported/imported and parsed using old-school NSXMLParser in Objective-C

Education People (Kent County Council) - Smarter Play - 2015

- Developed a universal App (iPhone and iPad) in Objective-C to educate parents on all things EYFS (Early Years Foundation Setting)
- Developed a realtime backend system to manage the app remotely using Bootstrap, PHP, async JS and HTML, also included push notifications
- Attended regular meetings with stakeholders on app progress and feature amendments and additions
- Supported the app/backend as per a maintenance contract for a couple of years
- App received several awards in its recognised industry

Web Developer/iOS Developer/I.T Manager — Talchemy — Ashford — 2016 - 2017

- Developed POC restaurant table service management system using Bootstrap, async JS, PHP and MySql
- Developed many web-scrapers to accumulate restaurant data from various online sources using Bootstrap, async JS, PHP and MySql
- Developed payroll input and output macros for Talchemy Talent Board using Bootstrap, async JS, PHP and MySql
- Developed POC online payroll system for a large recruitment agency in London using Bootstrap, Firebase, async JS, PHP and MySql
- Developed Bodicore website a 3D scanning system to monitor body posture and weight using Bootstrap
- Developed a Bodicore iOS app booking system using Pass-kit and backend system
- Solely managed a very small I.T infrastructure

Web Developer/I.T Administrator — IT Workshop — Ashford — 2013 - 2016

- Developed online tax legislation tests specifically IR35 & CIS for The Taxation Workshop sister company for Ltd company contractors in HTML and JS
- Developed Search to Find website and backend in HTML, JS and PHP (later became Talchemy)
- Develop custom CMS websites & Lead Generation systems for the group of sister umbrella companies under the Workshop Group of companies
- Supported a small I.T infrastructure of servers and desktops

Web Administrator/Developer — PageSuite— Ashford — 2011 - 2012

- iOS AppStore submissions
- 1st to 3rd line support of all internal systems using Microsoft products, support and administration of various web technologies including Amazon EC2 instances including Linux and Microsoft servers
- · Some minor ASPX development

Technical Design Analyst/I.T Administrator —Foster and Partners — London — 2011 - 2012

- Evaluation of computer hardware, software and solutions. Installation, recommendation and support of systems and solutions for the practice
- Solely supported the Visualisation teams and managed, administered and installed 50 render nodes for 3D rendering technologies including Autodesk Back-burner
- 1st, 2nd and occasional 3rd line IT Support of all workstations, laptops and back end servers in the Windows environment. Support and installation of over 100 applications

EDUCATION

Christ Church High School - 1990 - 1996 — 8 GCSE B - D

SKILLS

- Swift
- · Objective-C
- iOS Frameworks UIKIT ARKIT MAPKIT Core Bluetooth (To mention a few)
- Design patterns MVC MVVM
- Xcode
- GIT
- Bitrise
- HTML
- CSS
- JS
- PHP
- MYSQL
- Photoshop
- MAYA
- ZBrush